hello guys in this video I mean to show
you how you can download and install
Arduino IDE on your Windows 10 operating
system so let's get started first of all
open your favorite browser and search
for Arduino and the first result which
will appear here will be the Arduino
website so this is the Arduino website
which is Arduino dot C C right so just
enter into this website and the first
thing which will we will do here is to
download the Arduino executable right so
in this website we need to go to the
downloads section so just click download
and I can see here there is a Windows
installer here so I can just you know
install this using this windows
installer so just click Windows
installer which is going to download the
executable file for the windows and in
here if you want to contribute because
it's open-source project which will
depend upon your contribution so if you
want you can just give some of the
dollars which you want or otherwise you
can just say just it download and you
don't want to contribute right and this
is going to you know download this
Arduino Windows dot exe file so just
wait for a download to complete it's
going to take around a few seconds to a
minute
to download it and after it will
download we are going to continue to
install this arduino ide
now once the executable is downloaded
you just need to run it and once it runs
you just need to follow the instructions
so let me minimize my browser and i will
wait for the installation to start first
of all and this installation has been
started so first run
the control so just click yes here and
in here just read the document and
agreement and then just say I agree we
want to install all the things just
click Next
and this is the location where it will
be installed so just click install which
is going to start the installation
process of arduino ide now in between
you will say some permissions so if you
want to give the permission or not and
then you just need to press ok in that
situation so let's the let the process
run and we will go step by step right so
it's extracting all the things so just
wait for this to go to the 100% this
progress bar and then we will continue
ok so now it says would you like to
install this device software for Arduino
USB driver you just need to click
install and then continue and this time
it against asks and you just need to
click install once again and now you can
see the installation is complete you
will be able to see this message
completed and then you can close this
wizard and I can see on my desktop also
there is a arduino icon which I can
click and this is going to start the
arduino ide right so just double click
on this icon and this is going to start
this arduino ide
and in here you just need to give the
access to this software so just say
allow access and you can see the arduino
ide has been started now right now in
order to you know connect or flash your
arduino nem arduino you just need to go
to your folder explorer and then go to
your pc and right click on your pc and
then here click manage and in here
first of all you need to insert your
arduino hardware and using this hardware
you will be able to connect to the
arduino ide also so first insert your
hardware and this and in this computer
management click device manager and when
you have inserted your arduino hardware
correctly you will be able to see your
arduino here under you the ports right
now i haven't connected arduino ide so I
don't see any do we know but when you
connect your you know hardware correctly
then you will be able to see this
arduino here and then you will be able
to flash it using your arduino ide so i
hope you have enjoyed this video please
welcome and subscribe and bye